Guide to the Ira Vaughan Hiscock Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- OFFICE FILES, 1925-1939; Series II; 32.5 linear feet (78 boxes)
  - 1936 General Papers
    - New Haven Rotary Club (Box 59, Folder 1155-1156)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 59, Folder 1157)
    - New York City, A-Z (Box 59, Folder 1158)
    - New York, City of, Department of Health (Box 59, Folder 1159-1161)
    - New York, State of, Department of Health (Box 59, Folder 1162)
    - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc. (Box 60, Folder 1163)
    - O (Box 60, Folder 1164)
    - P (Box 60, Folder 1165)
    - Public Health Federation (Box 60, Folder 1166)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 60, Folder 1167)
    - Rosenwald (Julius) Fund (Box 60, Folder 1168)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 60, Folder 1169)
    - S (Box 60, Folder 1170)
    - San Francisco, County of, Department of Public Health (Box 60, Folder 1171)
    - Shepard, William P. (Box 60, Folder 1172)
    - Society of American Bacteriologists (Box 60, Folder 1173)
    - T (Box 60, Folder 1174)
    - Tennessee, University of (Box 60, Folder 1175)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 60, Folder 1176)
    - U-V (Box 60, Folder 1177)
    - United States, A-Z (Box 60, Folder 1178)
    - United States Treasury Department, Public Health Service (Box 60, Folder 1179-1180)
    - W (Box 60, Folder 1181)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 60, Folder 1182)
    - Winslow, C.-E. A. (Box 60, Folder 1183)
    - Y (Box 60, Folder 1184)
    - Yale University, A-Z (Box 60, Folder 1185)
    - Yale University Graduate Club (Box 60, Folder 1186-1187)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 60, Folder 1188-1192)
      - Restricted, 1936 (Box 87)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 61, Folder 1193-1201)
      - Restricted, 1936 (Box 87)
  - 1936 Writings (Box 61, Folder 1202-1204)
  - 1936 Writings (Box 62, Folder 1205-1217)
  - 1937 General Papers
    - A (Box 63, Folder 1218)
    - American, A-Z (Box 63, Folder 1219)
    - American Medical Association (Box 63, Folder 1220)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 63, Folder 1221-1228)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 64, Folder 1229)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 64, Folder 1230)
    - B (Box 64, Folder 1231)
    - Boy Scouts of America, National Council (Box 64, Folder 1232-1233)
    - Boy Scouts of America, Quinnipiac Council, New Haven (Box 64, Folder 1234-1237)
    - C (Box 64, Folder 1238)
    - California, A-Z (Box 65, Folder 1239)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 65, Folder 1240-1241)
    - Connecticut, A-Z (Box 65, Folder 1242)
    - Connecticut Conference of Social Work (Box 65, Folder 1243-1244)
    - Connecticut Public Health Association (Box 65, Folder 1245-1246)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, New Haven branch (Box 65, Folder 1247-1248)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 65, Folder 1249)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 65, Folder 1250)
    - D (Box 65, Folder 1251)
    - E (Box 65, Folder 1252)
    - F (Box 65, Folder 1253)
    - G (Box 65, Folder 1254)
    - Greenwich, Connecticut (Box 66, Folder 1255)
    - H (Box 66, Folder 1256)
    - Honolulu, Hawaii (Box 66, Folder 1257-1259)
    - I (Box 66, Folder 1260)
    - International Association of Milk Sanitarians (Box 66, Folder 1261)
    - J-K (Box 66, Folder 1262)
    - L (Box 66, Folder 1263)
    - Los Angeles, County of (Box 66, Folder 1264)
    - M (Box 66, Folder 1265)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (Box 66, Folder 1266)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 66, Folder 1267)
    - N (Box 66, Folder 1268)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, Inc. (Box 66, Folder 1269)
    - National Conference of Tuberculosis Secretaries (Box 66, Folder 1270)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 66, Folder 1271)
    - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 67, Folder 1272)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 67, Folder 1273-1274)
    - New Haven Chamber of Commerce (Box 67, Folder 1275)
    - New Haven Children's Community Center (Box 67, Folder 1276)
    - New Haven, City of, Department of Health (Box 67, Folder 1277-1280)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 67, Folder 1281-1289)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 68, Folder 1290-1298)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies (Box 68, Folder 1299)
    - New Haven, Family Society of (Box 68, Folder 1300)
    - New Haven Rotary Club (Box 69, Folder 1301-1302)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 69, Folder 1303-1304)
    - New York, City of (Box 69, Folder 1305-1308)
    - New York, City of, Department of Health (Box 69, Folder 1309-1312)
    - New York, City of, Department of Health (Box 70, Folder 1313)
    - O (Box 70, Folder 1314)
    - P (Box 70, Folder 1315)
    - R (Box 70, Folder 1316)
    - Rochester, New York (Box 70, Folder 1317)
    - S (Box 70, Folder 1318)
    - Society of American Bacteriologists (Box 70, Folder 1319)
    - T (Box 70, Folder 1320)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 70, Folder 1321)
    - U-V (Box 70, Folder 1322)
    - United States, A-Z (Box 70, Folder 1323)
    - W (Box 70, Folder 1324)
    - Warner Brothers (Box 70, Folder 1325)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 70, Folder 1326)
    - Yale University, A-Z (Box 70, Folder 1327-1329)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 71, Folder 1330-1343)
      - Restricted, 1937 (Box 87)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 72, Folder 1344)
      - Restricted, 1937 (Box 87)
  - 1937 Surveys
    - Colorado Springs survey (Box 72, Folder 1345-1347)
  - 1937 Writings (Box 72, Folder 1348)
  - 1938 General Papers
    - A (Box 72, Folder 1349)
    - American Medical Association (Box 72, Folder 1350)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 72, Folder 1351-1357)
    - American Red Cross, New Haven Chapter (Box 73, Folder 1358)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 73, Folder 1359-1360)
    - B (Box 73, Folder 1361)
    - Bauer, Walter W. (Box 73, Folder 1362)
    - Baumgartner, Leona (Box 73, Folder 1363)
    - Beebe, Elinor Lee (Box 73, Folder 1364)
    - Bishop, Eugene L. (Box 73, Folder 1365)
    - Boy Scouts of America, National Council (Box 73, Folder 1366-1369)
    - Boy Scouts of America, Quinnipiac Council, New Haven (Box 73, Folder 1370-1371)
    - C (Box 73, Folder 1372)
    - California, University of (Box 73, Folder 1373)
    - Colorado, A-Z (Box 73, Folder 1374)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 73, Folder 1375)
    - Connecticut, A-Z (Box 74, Folder 1376)
    - Connecticut Public Health Association (Box 74, Folder 1377)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene (Box 74, Folder 1378-1379)
    - Connecticut State Conference of Social Work (Box 74, Folder 1380)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 74, Folder 1381)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Education (Box 74, Folder 1382-1383)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 74, Folder 1384)
    - Connecticut, State of, Personnel Department (Box 74, Folder 1385)
    - D (Box 74, Folder 1386)
    - Davis, Michael M. (Box 74, Folder 1387)
    - Delta Omega Society (Box 74, Folder 1388)
    - E (Box 74, Folder 1389)
    - F (Box 74, Folder 1390)
    - G (Box 74, Folder 1391)
    - H (Box 74, Folder 1392)
    - Halverson, Wilton L. (Box 74, Folder 1393)
    - Hamden, Connecticut (Box 74, Folder 1394)
    - Hartford, City of, Board of Health (Box 74, Folder 1395)
    - Honolulu, Hawaii (Box 74, Folder 1396-1397)
    - International Association of Milk Sanitarians (Box 75, Folder 1398)
    - J-K (Box 75, Folder 1399)
    - Kellogg Foundation (Box 75, Folder 1400)
    - L (Box 75, Folder 1401)
    - M (Box 75, Folder 1402)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (Box 75, Folder 1403-1404)
    - Meyer, Karl F. (Box 75, Folder 1405)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 75, Folder 1405)
    - N (Box 75, Folder 1406)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene (Box 75, Folder 1407)
    - National Health Council, Inc. (Box 75, Folder 1408-1410)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 75, Folder 1411)
    - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, Inc. (Box 75, Folder 1412)
    - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 75, Folder 1413-1414)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 75, Folder 1415-1416)
    - New Haven Chamber of Commerce (Box 75, Folder 1417)
    - New Haven, City of, Department of Health (Box 75, Folder 1418)
    - New Haven, City of, Department of Health (Box 76, Folder 1419)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 76, Folder 1420-1424)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies (Box 76, Folder 1425-1426)
    - New Haven, Family Society of (Box 76, Folder 1427)
    - New Haven Social Hygiene Association (Box 76, Folder 1428)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 76, Folder 1429)
    - New York City, A-Z (Box 76, Folder 1430)
    - New York, City of, Department of Health (Box 76, Folder 1431-1432)
    - New York State Charities Aid Association (Box 76, Folder 1433)
    - New York, State of, Department of Health (Box 76, Folder 1434)
    - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc. (Box 76, Folder 1435)
    - O-R (Box 76, Folder 1436)
    - Rochester, New York (Box 77, Folder 1437)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 77, Folder 1437)
    - S-W (Box 77, Folder 1438)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 77, Folder 1439-1440)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 77, Folder 1441-1443)
      - Restricted, 1938 (Box 87)
  - 1938 Surveys
    - Honolulu tuberculosis survey (Box 77, Folder 1444)
  - 1938 Writings (Box 77, Folder 1445-1446)
  - 1939 General Papers
    - American Museum of Health, Inc. (Box 77, Folder 1447)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 77, Folder 1448-1453)
    - American Red Cross, New Haven Chapter (Box 77, Folder 1454)
    - B-C (Box 77, Folder 1455)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Health, New Haven branch (Box 78, Folder 1456)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 78, Folder 1457)
    - Emerson, Haven (Box 78, Folder 1458)
    - M (Box 78, Folder 1459)
    - N (Box 78, Folder 1460)
    - National Conference of Social Work (Box 78, Folder 1461)
    - National Dairy Council (Box 78, Folder 1462)
    - National Health Council, Inc. (Box 78, Folder 1463-1467)
    - National Organization of Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 78, Folder 1468)
    - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, Inc. (Box 78, Folder 1469-1472)
    - New England Health Education Institute (Box 78, Folder 1473)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 78, Folder 1474)
    - New Haven Chamber of Commerce (Box 78, Folder 1475)
    - New Haven, City of, Department of Health (Box 79, Folder 1476-1478)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 79, Folder 1479-1483)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies (Box 79, Folder 1484-1485)
    - New Haven, Family Society of (Box 79, Folder 1486)
    - New Haven Poliomyelitis Rehabilitation Fund (Box 79, Folder 1487)
    - New Haven Social Hygiene Association (Box 79, Folder 1488)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 79, Folder 1489)
    - New Rochelle, New York (Box 79, Folder 1490)
    - New York City, A-Z (Box 79, Folder 1491)
    - New York, City of, Department of Health (Box 79, Folder 1492-1493)
    - P (Box 80, Folder 1494)
    - R (Box 80, Folder 1495)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 80, Folder 1496)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 80, Folder 1496)
    - S (Box 80, Folder 1497)
    - Sinai, Nathan (Box 80, Folder 1498)
    - Sippy, John J. (Box 80, Folder 1498)
    - Social Work Today (Box 80, Folder 1499)
    - T (Box 80, Folder 1500)
    - United States, A-Z (Box 80, Folder 1501)
    - United States Department of Labor (Box 80, Folder 1502)
    - United States Treasury Department, Public Health Service (Box 80, Folder 1503)
    - Vaughan, Henry F. (Box 80, Folder 1504)
    - W (Box 80, Folder 1505)
    - Y (Box 80, Folder 1506)
    - Yale University (Box 80, Folder 1507)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 80, Folder 1508-1513)
      - Restricted, 1939 (Box 87)
  - 1939 Writings (Box 80, Folder 1514)
- OFFICE FILES, 1940-1979; Series III; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Material in this series is filed according to a filing code established, presumably, by the secretary of the Department of Public Health. The files are arranged alphabetically by code title rather than by code letter. Within each code category material is filed chronologically.
  - Acknowledgements, requests and engagements (code b.), 1947-1950 (Box 81, Folder 1515-1520)
  - Army (code h.), 1945-1954 (Box 81, Folder 1521-1530)
  - Committees and conferences (code c.), 1940-1943 (Box 81, Folder 1531-1533)
  - Committees and conferences (code c.), 1947-1950 (Box 82, Folder 1534-1537)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1958 (Box 82, Folder 1538-1552)
    - Restricted, 1940-1958 (Box 87)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1972, undated (Box 83, Folder 1553-1559)
  - Rotary Club of New Haven (code j.), 1949-1950 (Box 83, Folder 1560-1561)
  - Speaking engagements (code d.), 1944-1950 (Box 83, Folder 1562-1568)
  - Speaking engagements (code d.), 1951-1962 (Box 84, Folder 1569-1578)
  - Surveys (code g.), 1947-1956 (Box 84, Folder 1579-1582)
    - Restricted, 1947-1956 (Box 87)
  - Wesleyan University reunion (code f.), 1946-1954 (Box 85, Folder 1583-1590)
  - Writings (code e.), 1940-1958 (Box 85, Folder 1591-1603)
  - Writings (code e.), 1960-1979, undated (Box 86, Folder 1604-1613)
  - Yale University (code a.), 1947-1958 (Box 86, Folder 1614-1618)
- Appendix A: PUBLICATIONS BY HISCOCK IN YALE LIBRARIES
  - American Red Cross textbook on Red Cross home nursing, 1942
  - An appraisal of the public health program, San Francisco, California for the fiscal year 1929-1930, 1931
  - The Case of a premature infant showing the teaching of the social component of medicine, 1941
  - Child health study of eastern Oklahoma, 1951
  - Community health organization, 1927, 1932, 1939, 1950
  - District health administration, 1936
  - Joint authorship
    - Educational opportunities in school health administration, 1942
    - Health survey of North Haven, Ct., 1928
    - Health survey of Winsted, Ct. with others, 1930
    - Public health survey of Greenwich, Ct., 1925
    - School health supervision (pamphlet), 1923
    - A survey of public health activities in Colorado Springs and El Paso County, Colorado, 1937
    - Survey of public health activities in Honolulu, Hawaii, 1935
    - Ways to community health education, 1939
- Appendix B: INDEX TO SELECT CORRESPONDENCE
  - Addison, Sarah: Series II., folders 443, 711
  - American Medical Association: Series II., folder 1362
  - American Public Health Association
    - Series I., folders 3, 6, Series I
    - Series II., folders 693, 1088, Series II
  - Armstrong, Donald: Series II., folders 965, 970-972, 1266, 1466
  - Atwater, Reginald M.: Series II., folders 401, 588, 933, 1065, 1221, 1357, 1448-1453
  - Bauer, Walter W.: Series II., folders 508, 544, 793, 930, 1064-1065, 1088, 1220
  - Baumgartner, Leona: Series II., folders 1305-1308, 1450, 1492
  - Bigelow, George: Series II., folders 110, 137, 167, 249, 254, 609, 726
  - Bishop, Eugene L.: Series II., folders 169, 188, 280, 658, 902, 947, 1017, 1176, 1321
  - Borst, Homer W.: Series II., folders 951, 985-987, 992, 1281-1288
  - Brown, Paul H.: Series II., folders 760, 996
  - Buck, Carl E.: Series II., folders 416, 418, 424, 612, 688-689, 798, 930-933
  - Bundesen, Herman N.
    - Series I., folders 8, 10, Series I
    - Series II., folder 141, Series II
  - Bunnell, Sterling H.: Series II., folders 656, 768
  - Calver, Homer N.
    - Series I., folders 14, 25-27, Series I
    - Series II., folders 33, 61, 96, 139, 143, 209-210, 213, 300-303, 310, 335, 407, 551, 713, 795, 824, 934, 1065, 1224-1228, 1408-1410, 1447, 1451, 1464, Series II
  - Child Welfare League of America, Inc.: Series II., folder 335
  - Clarke, Walter: Series II., folders 314, 1359, 1408-1410, 1463
  - Cleveland Health Council: Series II., folder 335
  - Committee on Research in Medical Economics: Series II., folder 1387
  - Cumming, Hugh S.: Series II., folders 52, 517, 947
  - Dawson, John B.: Series II., folders 82, 115, 175, 265, 364-365, 369, 486, 632, 743, 850, 863, 873, 881, 985, 987, 1142
  - Deming, Dorothy: Series II., folders 471-472
  - Douglas, William O.: Series II., folder 409
  - Draper, Warren F.
    - Series I., folders 18-19, 27-28, Series I
    - Series II., folders 52, 385, 947, 1111, 1179, Series II
  - Dublin, Louis I.
    - Series I., folders 3, 6-10, 12, 14, 17-20, 24, 27, 29, Series I
    - Series II., folders 46, 551, 965, 1354, Series II
  - Eliot, Martha M.: Series II., folders 828, 1323, 1463
  - Emerson, Haven
    - Series I., folders 8, 10, 12-13, 16, 21, 27, Series I
    - Series II., folders 95, 137, 151, 207, 228, 449, 543, 569, 687, 792, 795, 1063, Series II
  - Emerson, Kendall: Series II., folders 54, 172, 254, 262, 355, 416-418, 547, 614, 617, 688, 795, 842, 846, 1131
  - Emery, E. VanNorman: Series II., folders 709, 951
  - Everett, Ray
    - Series I., folders 9, 18, 29, Series I
    - Series II., folder 146, Series II
  - Falk, Isidore S.
    - Series I., folders 16-17, Series I
    - Series II., folders 435, 451, 571, 840, 1124, 1501, Series II
  - Ferrell, John A.: Series II., folders 122, 446, 509, 582, 854, 1167, 1466, 1496
  - Folks, Homer: Series II., folder 1410
  - Fox, Elizabeth G.: Series II., folders 495, 760, 1002, 1304
  - Fraas, Alma W.: Series II., folders 209-210, 419
  - Galdston, Lago: Series II., folders 144, 179, 255, 271, 889, 1451
  - Galt, John R.: Series II., folders 405, 595, 832, 1111, 1257
  - Green, Howard W.: Series II., folders 253, 346, 434, 548, 569, 614, 842, 844, 946, 1091, 1126
  - Greenburg, Leonard
    - Series I., folder 13, Series I
    - Series II., folders 855, 982, 1305-1308, Series II
  - Grout, Ruth E.: Series II., folders 703, 945
  - Halverson, Wilton L.: Series II., folders 723, 896, 1010, 1450
  - Jay, Augusta E.: Series II., folders 209-210, 420, 695
  - Kingsbury, John A.: Series II., folders 344, 728, 966-967
  - Kleinschmidt, H. E.
    - Series I., folders 23, 25-26, Series I
    - Series II., folders 300-303, 1308, 1448, Series II
  - Knight, Howard R.: Series II., folders 350, 607, 843, 1461
  - Knowlton, Millard
    - Series I., folders 10-13, 15-19, 30, Series I
    - Series II., folders 68, 154, 585, 708, 711, Series II
  - Linde, Joseph I.: Series II., folders 888, 982, 1151, 1277, 1477, 1487
  - Mangold, Walter S.: Series II., folders 341, 463, 723, 836, 963, 1121, 1239, 1373
  - Marquette, Bleeker
    - Series I., folders 6, 8, Series I
    - Series II., folders 169, 182, 504, 1166, Series II
  - Mickle, Friend Lee: Series II., folders 64, 68, 154, 585, 711, 822, 1137
  - Midkiff, Frank E.: Series II., folders 1049-1052, 1113
  - Mountin, Joseph W.: Series II., folders 517, 1503
  - Murphy, John W.: Series II., folders 1418, 1481
  - National Committee of Health Council Executives: Series II., folders 242, 335
  - New York, City of, Department of Health: Series II., folder 1363
  - Northrup, Carl F.: Series II., folders 148, 221, 431, 700-701
  - Osborn, Stanley H.
    - Series I., folders 1, 7-12, 14, 17, 23, 26, 28-30, Series I
    - Series II., folders 59, 104, 154, 233, 326, 444, 582, 605, 646, 712, 760, 822, 860, 953, 1137, 1250, 1463, Series II
  - Palama Settlement: Series II., folders 1257-1259
  - Palmer, George T.
    - Series I., folder 22, Series I
    - Series II., folders 687, 1305-1312, Series II
  - Parran, Thomas: Series II., folders 499, 894, 1112, 1179, 1467, 1503
  - Patterson, Raymond S.: Series II., folders 455, 560, 600, 694
  - Peter, William W.: Series II., folders 143, 227, 552, 588
  - Platt, Philip S.
    - Series I., folders 7, 9, 22, 29, Series I
    - Series II., folders 58, 96, 144, 179, 213, 254, 271, 406, 595, 719, 832, Series II
  - Pomeroy, J. L.: Series II., folders 246, 463-465, 963, 1264
  - Preble, Paul
    - Series I., folders 20, 22, 27, Series I
    - Series II., folder 52, Series II
  - Rice, John L.
    - Series I., folders 18, 26, 28, Series I
    - Series II., folders 47, 81, 174, 264, 362-363, 484, 582, 640, 646, 708, 737, 857, 861, 873, 890, 1006, 1159, 1309-1313, 1431-1432, 1492, Series II
  - Roche, Josephine R.: Series II., folder 947
  - Roosevelt, Theodore: Series II., folders 1366-1369
  - Routzahn, Evart G.
    - Series I., folders 12, 28, Series I
    - Series II., folders 185, 510, 560, 616, 654, 765, 900, 1069, 1169, Series II
  - Scamman, Clarence L.: Series II., folders 110, 704-705, 814, 947-948
  - Scoville, Harry F.: Series II., folders 341, 836, 1121, 1264
  - Shephard, William P.: Series II., folder 553
  - Sigerist, Henry: Series II., folder 1040
  - Sippy, John J.: Series II., folder 858
  - Smith, Barry C.: Series II., folder 704-705, 947-948
  - Snow, William F.
    - Series I., folder 29, Series I
    - Series II., folders 34, 146, 164, 563, 697, 732, 805, 844, 936, 1069, 1466, Series II
  - Sydenstricker, Edgar: Series II., folders 190, 250, 344, 468, 610, 728, 839, 947, 966-967, 1124
  - Tennessee Valley Authority: Series II., folder 1365
  - Thompson, Lewis R.: Series II., folder 52
  - Tobey, James A.
    - Series I., folders 28, 30, Series I
    - Series II., folders 597, 959, Series II
  - Trotter, Frederick E.: Series II., folders 403, 595, 719, 1049-1052, 1113, 1257-1259
  - Tucker, Katherine: Series II., folders 354, 471-474, 733
  - Vaughn, Henry F.
    - Series I., folders 8-12, 16-17, Series I
    - Series II., folders 155, 236, 447, 547, 554, 587, 625, 691, 796, 1102, Series II
  - Vreeland, Herbert H.: Series II., folders 718, 957, 1153
  - Walker, W. Frank: Series II., folders 32, 63, 96, 139, 164, 209-210, 213, 300-304, 402, 424, 436, 560-561, 574, 705, 713, 814, 854, 947-948, 1092, 1225-1228, 1240-1241, 1352-1354, 1375, 1448-1453
  - West, James E.: Series II., folders 939-940, 1368
  - Widdemer, Kenneth D.: Series II., folders 498, 611, 612, 762, 892, 1006, 1451, 1493
  - Williams, Huntington: Series II., folders 689, 938
  - Wilson, Charles C.: Series II., folder 1110
  - Winslow, Anne R. (Mrs. C.-E.A.): Series II., folders 117, 494, 639, 1096
  - Winslow, C.-E.A.
    - Series I., folders 1-3, 6, 12, 14, 23-24, 30, Series I
    - Series II., folders 55, 91, 416, 582, 630, 641, 774-776, 820, 841, 864, 910, 985-986, 1025, 1027, 1096, 1097, 1408, Series II
  - Yale Athletes Mortality Study: Series II., folder 204
  - Zimand, Savel: Series II., folders 428, 556, 565, 612, 699